# Gopal Tiwari

Big Data Developer at QuintilesIMS

gopal.tiwari2012@gmail.com

## Summary

BigData | Spark 2 | Scala | Kafka | Hadoop | Streaming | ElasticSearch | Kibana | Cassandra | Hive | Impala

Adroit Open Source and Big Data enthusiast working as Developer with QuintilesIMS, having an experience of more than 5 years in product development with scala, java & c#.

Advanced technical experience on ETL solutions for Big Data using Apache Spark, Kafka, Hive, Impala, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana and Cassandra.

Having proclivity towards learning new technologies and languages. Loves exploring new languages & technologies. Always finds time to blog key ideas that I discovered while solving challenging problems.

## Experience

Big Data Developer at QuintilesIMS December 2016 - Present

Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys

February 2014 - November 2016 (2 years 10 months)

Big Data Development with Apache Spark, ElasticSearch Kibana & Kafka. Coding involves languages like Java, Scala & C#.

#### Software Developer

July 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Application development responsibilities for front-end, back-end & database development which involves technologies like ASP.NET jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, SignalR, ADO.NET and MS SQL Server.

## Education

Uttar Pradesh Technical University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science & Engineering, 2008 - 2012

Activities and Societies: Seminars, Robotics Club, Paper Presentations

# Honors and Awards

Awarded Honorable Mention in "International Innovative Application Competition", Secured 2nd position in IBM National Software Demonstration Competition, Selected in Top 18 Software Projects of India, Above And Beyond

# **Gopal Tiwari**

Big Data Developer at QuintilesIMS

gopal.tiwari2012@gmail.com



Contact Gopal on LinkedIn